shudder.com 2019-04-04

# Privacy Policy | SHUDDER

Effective Date: May, 2018

This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes what information Shudder LLC and its affiliate and subsidiary(collectively, “Shudder,” “we,” “our,” or “us,”) collect about you, how we use and shareinformation, and the choices you have about our information collection and processing inwith your use of the Shudder Services (defined below). You can find our address andcontact information in Section 12 below.

 **1\. WHAT IS THE SCOPE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**

“Shudder Services,” means the services provided and made available by Shudder LLC and its affiliates (collectively, "Shudder", "we", "our" or "us") in connection with your browsing and viewing of Shudder multimedia (such as movies and television shows) ("Content") through Shudder websites, applications, or other interfaces and platforms. The Shudder Services also include any other technologies, features, and content we may provide or use on the user interfaces. This Policy is incorporated into the Shudder Terms of Use. It is designed to inform you (referred to here as "you," "your" or "yourself") about how and why we collect, manage, retain, use, and share information related to you and your use of the Shudder Services.

 **2\. WILL THIS POLICY EVER CHANGE?**

We may change this Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will post the new version hererevise the “Effective Date” above. If we make any material changes to this Policy, we will alsoyou by email, by means of a notice on the Shudder Services, or by other reasonable means.encourage you to review the Policy whenever you use our Shudder Services to stay informedour information practices and the choices available to you.

 **3\. WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED FROM ME?**

Information you provide to us: 

You may be required to submit information to us. For example, the process of creating or editinguser profile may require you to provide us with a name, e-mail address, phone number,address (including postal code), password of your choice and cable provider; if you do notyour name or other identifying information, we may not be able to respond to your inquiriespost your content; and if you do not provide us with your username and password, you will not beto access your online account.

When you personalize your profile and use the features of the Shudder Services, we will collect anyyou voluntarily provide, and we may also request optional information to support yourof the Shudder Services, such as a profile picture and birthday. Additionally, we collect anythat you voluntarily enter into any postings, comments or forums within the Shudder Services, including private messages you send to other users of the Shudder Services. And, if youus, we will collect your e-mail address and the full content of your e-mail, including attachedand other information you choose to provide to us.

Information We Collect Automatically From Your Devices:

When you use or access Shudder Services, we collect certain information about your device anduse of the Shudder Services automatically.

For example, we collect information about the device you use to access the Shudder Services,hardware model, operating system and version, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address and otherdevice identifiers, mobile network information and information about the device’s interactionour Shudder Services. We also collect information about how you use Shudder Services,your access times, browser types, and language preferences. We collect information aboutyou have opened or clicked on links in our HTML emails. This type of data enables us tohow often individuals use parts of the Shudder Services so we can analyze and improve

We collect this information using cookies (i.e., small pieces of electronic information stored by yourbrowser software on to your computer’s hard drive), web beacons (i.e., small pieces of datain images on the Shudder Services), and similar technologies. We use the informationvia these tools to understand which Content, User Content, marketing and advertisements,have seen or accessed and to help us identify unique users to our Shudder Services. We useaccess cookies to enable us to provide you with personalized Content, User Content andso that we can customize areas of the Shudder Services based on your activities andinterests.

Please see our Cookies Policy for more information about our use of these technologies and the choices you may have. 

Location Information:

We collect different types of information about your location, including general information, such ascity, state and/or postal code associated with your IP Address, and, if you agree, more specificinformation that is provided through the GPS functionality on mobile devices used to accessShudder Services.

We may use such location information to customize the Shudder Services, including advertising thatpresented to you. For example, if you provide a postal code that indicates that you live in acity, the Shudder Services may be customized with information, features, orspecific to that city. In order to do this, your location information may be passedto our affiliates, agents, vendors or advertisers as described more fully below.

If you do not want your device to provide us with location-tracking information, do not agree to allowdevice to share this information with us or disable the GPS or other location-tracking functionsyour device, provided your device allows you to do this. Your device manufacturer may provideon how to disable GPS or other location-tracking functions. If you initially consent to theof location information, you can subsequently stop our collection of location information attime by changing the preferences on your mobile device or by uninstalling the application frommobile device by following the standard uninstall process to remove applications from your

Payment Information:

If you purchase a product or service through the Shudder Services, our third party paymentwill collect the billing and financial information they need to process your charges. Thisinclude your postal address, email address and financial information. We do not directly collectstore your financial information, like credit card numbers. However, our third party paymentmay share non-financial information with us related to your purchases, like your name,address and items purchased in order to fulfill your order.

Additional Information Collection Practices:

Some parts of the Shudder Services contain embedded content or links to content controlled by third parties. third parties may collect information about you when you access their content.

Should you choose to access such third-party content, you should review their privacy policies to ensure you and are comfortable with their practices concerning your information. We do not accept, and do disclaim, responsibility for the privacy policies and information collection, use, and sharing practices of any third party (whether or not such site is linked on or to the Sites). These links are provided to you for convenience purposes only, and you access them at own risk. 

We obtain information about you and your use of the Shudder Services from third parties like webproviders, analytics providers, social media platforms, data suppliers, and advertising

The information we collect in this manner includes your known or inferred age, gender, contact information, information about your demographics and interests, and information about the devices you use to access online services.

We may combine the information you provide us and information we automatically collect withthat we collect from public or third-party sources. Analytics providers and advertisingmay analyze the information they collect from online and other sources to provide us withinformation about your demographics and interests, such as your age range and theof products or services that may interest you. You may give us permission to access your information, including personally identifiable information from services offered by third parties,social media networks. For example, to access the Shudder Services, you may choose tousing your social media credentials, which allows us to obtain information from your socialaccount, such as your friends or contacts, profile picture, birthdate, gender, or other profile-information and any other information you have opted to share via the platform. Thewe obtain from such third party services depends on your account/privacy settings withthird parties and the third parties’ privacy policies.

We collect, store, use, and share the information we collect from third parties in accordance with this

 **4\. HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION?**

We use the information we collect to provide you with services in accord with the contracts we maywith you, to communicate with you, and to manage and improve our services, as permitted bylaws.

We use your personal information to:

  * provide you with services so that we can meet our contractual obligations to you. If theare not governed by a contract, we use your information to meet our businessin providing quality services to you;
  * respond to your requests for information, on the basis that it is in our business interests toto your requests, and you have requested that we do this;
  * process transactions, as necessary to meet our contractual obligations to you;
  * improve the Shudder Services and learn about how visitors use the Shudder Services. Thisnecessary for us to improve the content and features we offer through the Shudder Services, benefits you as it helps us make the Shudder Services more usable and appealing;
  * communicate with you about our products and services, including behavioral advertising, andyou with information about features on the Shudder Services and possible changesour Privacy Policy or terms of use. If required by applicable law, we will only sendon the basis that you have consented, or otherwise it will be to meet our businessin providing information to you about new products and features. You can opt out ofmarketing communications at any time;
  * communicate with you about third-party products and services that may be of interest to you,via behavioral advertising. If required by applicable law, we will only sendon the basis that you have consented, or otherwise it will be to meet our businessin expanding our business opportunities and providing information to you aboutproducts and services. You can opt out of receiving marketing communications attime;
  * make inferences about your interests, as necessary to meet our business interest inour business opportunities and learning how to make our services more relevantyou and other uses;
  * comply with legal obligations; and
  * protect our rights, your rights, and the rights of others, as this may be necessary to meet ourhigh standards of business practice.

We may use aggregated and/or de-identified data or other data that does not constitute personalunder applicable laws for any purpose, including, without limitation, in statistical analyses tous analyze patterns in the use of the Shudder Services.

When we analyze the personal information we collect for advertising, marketing, security, and fraud prevention, use automated processes to identify or predict potential risks or outcomes.

For example, we may use the information you provide us and information about your online activitiesinfer your interests. And we use those inferences to support automated decisions about the content, recommendations, offers we present to you on our digital properties. We use automated tools to identify suspicious activities associated with the Shudder Services (e.g., multiplefrom different locations within a short period of time). These automated processing activitiesnot, without human intervention, have legal or similar effects for you.

 **5\. How We Share Information**

We may disclose information when you ask us to do so or otherwise consent to the disclosure. Ifwould like to withdraw your consent that you may have provided, please use the mechanismsmay have been presented to you at the time we obtained your consent or contact us via thelisted below.

We share information with third parties that act on our behalf in association with the operation of theServices or associated activities.

Except as otherwise disclosed in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise communicated to you, we takesteps require these companies to collect, store, and use information about you only onbehalf and in accord with this Privacy Policy. Service providers include web hosting providers,services, shipping providers, and data storage providers. We share personal information withproviders on the basis that it is necessary to meet our legitimate interests in efficientlyour business and for developing future business.

We will share information about you with third parties when you engage in certain activities on theServices that are sponsored by third parties. For example, you may choose to purchaseor services offered by a third party or elect to receive information or communications from aparty. When you engage in such third-party, co-sponsored, or co-branded offerings, we mayinformation (e.g., your e-mail address) with third parties in association with the offerings.

We disclose this information to third parties for the purposes and on the basis described above (see

4), for example, to process your transactions and to respond to your requests for informationcommunications from third parties.

We engage third-party analytics providers to help us understand how users engage with the Sites.third parties may use cookies and similar technologies to collect information about your use of the Sites as well as information about your use of other websites over time.

The third-party services we use include, but may not be limited to: [Google Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245) [Adobe, ](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html)may provide you with choices about how they collect and use information. We share personalwith analytics providers on the basis that it is necessary to meet our legitimate interestsefficiently managing our business and for developing future business.

From time to time, we share your information with our affiliates and subsidiaries, or with our otherin connection with the purposes described in Section 4 above.

We may disclose information when we believe in good faith that such disclosures:

  * are required by law, including, for example, to comply with a court order or subpoena, or into a law enforcement agency's request;
  * will help to protect our rights or enforce our Terms of Use;
  * will support our detection, prevention, or response to fraud or intellectual property infringement;
  * will help protect your safety or security, including the safety and security of property that belongs to you;

We may also share information about you to the extent reasonably necessary to proceed with the consideration, negotiation, completion of a merger, reorganization, or acquisition of our business, or a sale, liquidation, or transfer of some or all of our assets.

The above-described disclosures are provided on the basis that they are either necessary to complyour legal obligations or they are necessary to meet our legitimate interests in managing ourefficiently and for developing future business.

Additionally, we reserve the right to share with third parties information that does not identify you (and cannot be combined with other information accessible to us to identify you) for any purpose.

 **6\. RETENTION OF INFORMATION**

We will retain the information that identifies you as an individual for as long as we have awith you and for a period after our relationship with you has ended. 

When deciding how long to keep your personal information after our relationship with you has ended, take into account how long we need to retain the information to fulfill the purposesabove and to comply with our legal obligations, including obligations to financial services regulators.may also retain personal information to investigate or defend against potential legalin accordance with the limitation periods of countries where legal action may be brought.

 **7\. SECURITY**

We have implemented commercially reasonable technical, administrative, and physical securityto protect the information that we collect or receive. From time to time, we review andupdates for our security procedures. Please be aware that, despite our ongoing efforts, nomeasures are perfect or impenetrable.

 **8\. IF YOU ARE UNDER 18**

If you are aged 18 or under you are not permitted to register on this Shudder Services or provide usany personal information. You are otherwise entitled to use the Shudder Services with theof your parent or guardian.

 **9\. YOUR CHOICES AND RIGHTS**

If you no longer wish to receive marketing materials from us, you can let us know by contacting us at privacy@shudder.com by clicking the 'unsubscribe' link or using other unsubscribe features thatprovide in our marketing communications.

Subject to local law, you may have certain additional rights regarding your personal information.

These may include the following rights to: access your personal information; rectify the informationhold about you; erase your personal information; restrict our use of your personal information;in a usable electronic format and transmit it to a third party (also known as the right ofportability); and lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority, and withdraw anyyou have given to uses of your personal information. If you would like to discuss or exerciserights you may have, feel free to contact us at privacy@shudder.com.

Please see our Cookies Policy for information about choices you may have regarding the processinginformation collected via Cookies and similar technologies.

 **10\. CHATROOM, FORUMS, COMMENTS, AND OTHER USER CONTENT**

We remind you that chat rooms, forums, comments and areas of our Shudder Services that allowto submit User Content on our Shudder Services are for public viewing and discussion. Anyinformation supplied by you in the public areas of the Shudder Services is widely

 **11\. WHERE IS INFORMATION PROCESSED?**

We process information collected via the Shudder Services in and subject to the laws of the United States, may not provide the same level protection for your information as your home country.information may be available to the United States government or its agencies under a lawfulmade in the United States. In addition, we may transfer your information outside the Unitedto our affiliates, business partners, and service providers located in other countries.

In some cases, your personal information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in a countryis not regarded as ensuring an adequate level of protection for personal information underUnion or other applicable laws. However, we have put in place appropriate safeguards (such as standard clauses approved by the European Commission) in accordance withlegal requirements to ensure that your data is adequately protected. For moreon the appropriate safeguards in place or to obtain a copy, contact us at privacy@shudder.com.

 **12\. HOW CAN I CONTACT YOU?**

If you have questions or concerns about our Policy, please contact us at: [privacy@shudder.com.](mailto:privacy@shudder.com)

Shudder LLC   
C/O Privacy  
11 Penn Plaza  
New York, NY 10001  
AMC Networks International - Iberia  
C/O AMCNI European Data Protection Officer  
Calle Saturno 1 - Pozuelo de Alarcon  
28224 Madrid  
dpo@amcnetworks.com

 **13\. INFORMATION ABOUT SOCIAL PLUGINS**

Our Shudder Services may make use of social network plugins. When you use a Service thatplugins, information may be directly transferred from you to the operator of a social network. information about the social network operators of plugins used in our Shudder Services, please see below:

Facebook: Data Controller: Facebook Ireland Limited, Hanover Reach, 5-7 Hanover Quay, 2 Dublin, Ireland. more information about Facebook’s privacy practices, please review their privacy policy.

Google+: Data Controller: Google, Inc., Ampitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA94043, USA. more information about Google’s privacy practices, please review their privacy policy.

Twitter: Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA. Forinformation about Twitter’s privacy practices, please review their privacy policy.
